Viet Quoc Pham

Personal Data

OFFICE: 4.10, CONNECT Centre, 34 Westland Row, 8PRX+RV Dublin, Ireland

PHONE: (+353) 083 475 5354 Емаіі: viet.pham@tcd.ie

Personal Site: https://phamqv.github.io/ Official Site: http://people.tcd.ie/phamq

Profiles: Google Scholar, ResearchGate, Publons, Scopus, LinkedIn, and ORCID

OVERVIEW

I am an Assistant Professor in Networks and Distributed Systems in the School of Computer Science and Statistics at Trinity College Dublin, the University of Dublin. I am also associated with CONNECT, an SFI centre for future networks and communications, and AdvanceCRT, an SFI centre for research training in advanced networks for sustainable societies, where I lead the COmputing, Intelligence, and Networking (COIN) research group. My research interest is to employ an arsenal of mathematical tools such as convex optimization, game theory, and machine learning to design, analyze, and optimize complex networks and applications such as cloud edge computing, 6G wireless networks, metaverse, blockchain, and wireless AI. While my work addresses research aspects of the interplay between AI and wireless, I am also interested in multidisciplinary research to leverage expertise from different sciences and disciplines.

EDUCATION

| Aug. 2017 | Doctor of Engineering in Telecommunications, Inje University, Kimhae, Korea |
|-----------|---|
| | Prize: Best Ph.D. Dissertation Award, Ranking #1 in Engineering |
| Aug. 2015 | Master of Science in Telecommunications, Inje University, Kimhae, Korea |
| Aug. 2013 | Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Telecommunications, |
| | Hanoi University of Science and Technology, Hanoi, Vietnam |

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

| Jan. 2023 - Current | Assistant Professor in Networks and Distributed Systems, |
|-----------------------|--|
| | School of Computer Science and Statistics, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland |
| Jan. 2023 - Current | TCD Supervisor, SFI ADVANCE CRT, Ireland |
| Jan. 2023 - Current | Associate Investigator, SFI CONNECT, Ireland |
| Jan. 2020 - Jan. 2023 | Research Professor, Pusan National University, Korea |
| Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019 | Research Professor, Changwon National University/Inje University, Korea |
| Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2018 | Post-Doctoral Research Fellow, Kyung Hee University, Korea |
| Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017 | Research Assistant, Inje University, Korea |
| Feb. 2012 - Aug. 2013 | Research Assistant, Hanoi University of Science and Technology, Vietnam |
| | |

FIELDS OF RESEARCH INTEREST

- COmputing: cloud edge computing, aerial computing, edge of things, and edge AI.
- Intelligence: wireless AI, deep learning, deep reinforcement learning, and federated learning.
- Networking: 6G wireless, IoT, intelligent surfaces, metaverse, and blockchain.